Ostateczna, stworzona przez człowieka,
wielozadaniowa maszyna bojowa.
Sztuczny człowiek, Evangelion.
Ikari Shinji...
Będziesz pilotem.
Pilotuj go!
Nie ma szans żebym to zrobił!
Jeśli masz zamiar go pilotować
zrób to teraz. Jeśli nie... wyjdź!
Nie mogę uciekać, nie mogę uciekać, nie mogę uciekać...
Nie mogę uciekać!
Będę pilotem.
Nasza Eva może pokonać Anioła...
Nasza przyszłość zależy od pokonania Aniołów.
Piętnaście lat temu,
połowa ludzkości zmarła w Drugim Uderzeniu.
Jeśli Anioły wywołają Trzecie Uderzenie,
Ludzkość wymrze. Nikt nie przeżyje.
Dlaczego tu jestem?
Nie wierzysz w dzieło ojca?
Oprócz pilotowania Evy, nie mam innego wyboru, prawda?
Mimo wszystko, to jedyny powód
dla którego ojeciec po mnie zadzwonił.
Dlatego nie mam innego wyboru
poza pilotowaniem Evy.
To czy nadal chcesz być pilotem Evy
zależy wyłącznie od Ciebie.
Będę pilotem.. jeszcze jeden raz...
Nie zginiesz, będę Cię chronić.
Nie uciekł od pilotowania Evy.
He chose not to step down of his own volition.
We should entrust this to him!
(Toji) We're counting on you!
(Kensuke) Do your best!
(Misato) Good luck!
Farewell.
I have nothing else.
Ayanami!
I don't know
what kind of expression
I should have at a time like this...
It'd be best if you smiled, I think.
These poor children's fates
have already been determined.
Captain Shikinami Asuka Langley,
the pilot of EVA Unit 02.
Are you stupid?!
So there are actually people
who happily pilot Evas.
(Misato) So, you don’t get along with your father.
(Shinji) He praised me for the first time in my life today.
Well done, Shinji.
I believe it’s the first time
praise has made me happy.
The Human Instrumentality Project...
What on Earth is NERV
doing behind the scenes?
Protect Katsuragi for me.
Being with Ikari makes me
warm and content.
That means you’re in love with him!
You’re interesting.
There is happiness to be found
outside of piloting EVA.
But Asuka’s still inside, Father!
Doesn’t matter. That thing is an Angel.
Stop!
It’s Father’s fault!
You’re running away again?
What’s wrong with running away
from things you hate?!
I don’t want to pilot EVA ever again.
You know, you won’t have any fun
if you keep fretting like that.
Even if Ikari won’t pilot EVA,
I’ll make it all right!
I am the pilot of Evangelion Unit 01…
Ikari Shinji!
At least Ayanami…
I’ll definitely save her!
Go for it, Shinji!
It’s for the sake of your own wishes!
Even if I disappear, I’ll be replaced.
Ayanami! Come!
I’m sorry. I couldn’t do anything.
It's fine.
I'm fine with this.
It’s the continuation of the Second Impact.
The Third Impact has begun.
(Kaworu) Now, the Promised time has come, Ikari Shinji.
(Ritsuko) The world is about to end.
Ikari Shinji.
From now on you won't be doing anything.
Are you sure I don't need to go out there, Misato?!
It doesn't make sense, Misato!
How'd things end up this way?
It's ridiculous!
Fourteen years have passed since then.
We are Wille, an organization
dedicated to destroying NERV.
I'm Kaworu. Nagisa Kaworu.
I'm a child bound by fate, just like you.
Evangelion Unit 13,
for you and that pilot.
Please just don't pilot the Eva!
Ayanami Rei doesn't exist anymore.
That's a lie!
Eva Unit 01 awakened
and opened the Doors of Guf,
acting as the trigger of the Third Impact.
You're the cause of all this.
(Shinji) Then I saved you back then, didn't I?
(Rei) I don't know.
Let's start, Fuyutsuki.
Brat Shinji,
are you trying to
cause the Third Impact again?
I'll take the spears for Kaworu's
and everyone else's sake.
That way, the world will be restored.
Then even Misato would...
Misato, use the DSS Choker!
(Kaworu) Stop, Shinji.
(Asuka) Stop, you stupid brat!
What is this?
It's the Fourth Impact.
Its starting ritual.
Is this my fault?
Is it because I pulled out the spears?
I was ordered to.
Don't look at me like that.
We'll meet again, Shinji.
Kaworu!
(Shinji) Nothing good ever came out of piloting the Eva!
(Asuka) You're such a brat.
However, there is no unforgivable sin.
There is always hope.
No matter the circumstances.
Paris Assault fleet ready.
Descending at Point 0 of the old city.
All ships, assume a defensive position.
Slow forward.
Gravity control, autonomous behavior
and guidance system: all clear.
Paris's sky is clear all around.
Category 6 core-converted surface.
Verifying ship coordinates.
She's arrived at the operation's starting point.
Roger.
All ships, switch to alert mode.
Eva-08 and DSRV descending to the target.
Landing pad anchors, normal.
The DSRV has locked into position
The DSRV has landed.
Analyzing the atmospheric composition.
Oxygen density reads at -3.
CO² is tolerable.
We can land here.
Roger. Let's start the mission.
It's been 16 years since I last came here.
Look at what's become of the famous City of Light...
It breaks my heart.
The L-Barrier density is quite high.
Restoring the Euro-NERV 1st Sealing Pillar
can take no longer than 720 seconds.
Why's that?
It's 180 seconds less than planned!
Is that enough for them to pick us up?
Seriously, I wish the pilots were the only ones
who wore these ridiculous suits.
Shut your yap and get to work!
Do you think we'll be able to activate the Anti-L system?
A recovery should be possible in stage 4.
We should thank our predecessors for that.
--"I leave it to you"
We will uphold your wish to save the city.
Let's get to work.
Well, they're here!
Eva 44A, customized aerial type!
Closing in at 4 o'clock!
Such a splendid front-line formation.
They formed a colony by themselves.
They're like a new creature now.
I need you to intercept.
Give us 560 more seconds.
Yes ma'am!
It'd be a pleasure to handle the 44A for you!
Alright, Nagara honey.
My cable flight is in your hands!
Now let's see...
Direction, turning, tilting...
Interesting, but...
This setup is really odd.
I wish they'd at least kept human joint articulation.
Eva-08, engagement of first wave of 44As in progress.
Second wave detected.
As planned, all 44As are attracted to Eva-08.
420 seconds remaining for the operation.
This is so slow, Boss.
It's like working on an 8-bit PC.
This system is as cryptic as the Evas.
It's not easy to control these using human language.
Stage 4 clear. We're falling behind.
Stay calm and hurry.
Yes ma'am.
Maintain speed. Plus 20 to guiding.
Keep the current tilt.
Full steam ahead!
You're not getting away!
Whoops.
The 4th wave is coming!
One against many.
As they say, "Many a small bird
drive away a hawk."
360 seconds remaining.
I can't get past stage 5.
You're hopeless, just keep trying.
Impossible!
We don't have enough time to replace the data.
Nothing is impossible!
Add more bypass!
But Boss, we just
don't have enough time!
Stop whining!
That's why I hate young guys.
Assholes!
Buncha losers!
Come on, bring it!
That was too easy!
What's this...?
Using Angel-style lures?
You little devils!
Be careful!
Their leader's here!
A military use of the Evas,
forbidden by the Vatican Treaty.
Together they make quite a threat.
A ground combat-type 4444C armed with a
positron cannon and 44Bs modified to feed power.
Deputy Commander Fuyutsuki
must be testing us.
The 44B's high energy
levels are rising!
All ships, take defensive measures.
Prepare for impact and EM pulse.
The 4444C is now in shooting position.
The 44Bs are generating a massive amount of power.
It's being fed to the ultra-high voltage system!
All 4444C power systems are now online.
Positronic acceleration in final phase!
The breech is locked!
Incoming!
Made it just in time!
If they fire again, we're toast!
44Bs are generating high power levels again.
The energy is being stored
in the high power feed system.
Already?!
4444C has started its engine.
It's ready to fire!
We're screwed!
Second shot incoming!
This is really, really bad!
Nagara sweetie, a little help!
Roger.
That's not gonna stop me!
Excuse-moi Eiffel.
4444C has gone completely silent.
Remaining operation time, 30 seconds!
We're using C to analyze the algorithm.
- The final lock has been deactivated!
Anti-L system, stage 5 completed!
It's activating, XO!
Restoring the former city of Paris.
Euro-Nerv's installation system is rebooting.
Systems are online.
Good work, Maya.
That was a close shave.
Mission complete.
Misato, come pick up the gear.
Roger.
Hovering down to the supply point.
All hands, prepare for resupply.
Prioritize spare parts and Eva munitions.
Drop the logistic support ships.
The ship is coming!
We need the parts to rebuild Eva-02.
To the victor go the spoils.
Now we have the parts to make Eva-02 like new,
and we can modify Eva-08 to make it
Overlap-compatible.
Wherever you are,
I'll come get you.
Just hold tight, Puppy Boy.
Tsch, coward.
Sorry, I'm late. Are you alright? Ikari.
Hah!
Ah-
Hey, dogs shouldn't go in there.
Oh?
So, you awake?
Don't you get it? It's me,
Toji, Suzuhara Toji.
It's been a really long time, Shinji.
I was surprised when you were brought in.
I did hear about your situation,
but I didn't get much of that weird talk.
Anyway, I'm glad you seem to be good.
Can you move already?
Seems like you can.
Well then, shall we head home?
You must be hungry.
It's a bit cold outside.
Doctor, it seems this child doesn't
want to change clothes.
Well, I guess this will do then.
Also, we're nearly out of Tamiflu.
Alright,
I'll talk with the head of the division.
Sorry, but I think
I'll be calling it a day.
Well then, shall we go?
There are so many incredible people here.
Is this somehow your first time in a crowd?
This is one of the settlements
where various survivors have gathered.
The third village.
About a thousand people live here.
That's a food distribution center.
It gets distributed three times a week.
Good morning Doctor.
Oh, Matsukata, already at work?
Please don't overdo it.
Doctor, are those two the kids
that Kredit asked you to look after?
Well, something like that.
Please take care of them.
Will do.
Well then, if you'll excuse me.
Yes.
What is "Kredit"?
Kredit is a support organization
created by Wille
and it doesn't just provide supplies,
it also helps with our commerce
with other villages.
Our village cannot survive on its own.
What is that?
It doesn't look like a dog.
Huh? That's a cat.
A cat?
Is it also the first time
you've seen a cat?
There's about ten living under the cars.
Here, not only there are cats and dogs,
but they are happy.
This here is our house,
and, though it's old, it is nice.
I was given the luxury of a house.
We're home.
Dinner will be ready soon.
Eh, let's see.
Sorry to have kept you all waiting.
Please eat while it's still hot.
Shinji, you must be hungry too,
yet you haven't eaten a thing.
Well, it's fine. Whenever you get hungry,
you can always come here.
(Toji) Thanks for the food!
(Old man) Thanks for the food!
So? It's good.
It gets weirdly flaky inside the mouth.
That means it's good.
Since my daughter has prepared
everything with care.
Wouldn't be a surprise
if I had met the best wife in the world.
I'm home.
Sorry for being late.
Oh! Welcome back, we've been waiting.
Shinji, do you know who it is?
My wife.
The class representative.
When I got your message,
I could hardly believe it.
Even having them in front of me,
it still feels like a dream.
It's been a while,
Ikari, Ayanami.
You're wrong, I'm not Ayanami.
What, you aren't? Well...
(Toji) Miss Lookalike then.
(Hikari) Miss Lookalike it is.
What's this?
Our daughter Tsubame.
She's so cute.
She's a person, yet she's small.
Why did you make her small?
What?
Have you never seen a baby either?
When they're born,
they're very small.
Babies gradually get bigger.
Isn't she cute?
That's right, isn't she cute?
That's because she's our daughter.
Ah, sorry.
Did you get scared
when he got loud?
I'm sorry Tsubame,
did I make you cry?
Ohh, the appearance of the general.
Sorry, I'm late.
Ohhh!
What is she doing?
Babies drink milk and
grow bigger.
Miss Lookalike, you're still no good.
I don't get it.
What would Ayanami Rei do?
You are different than Ayanami.
So you should be doing what you want.
Is it alright if I'm different?
(♪) That's what I have yet...
It's been a while, Ikari.
It's Aida, Aida Kensuke.
Right.
It's Kensuke,
the one who saved you.
This "survival otaku" is also
the one who remarkably saved us.
If he hadn't been there, we too
would have died out there long ago.
Shinji, it's fine if you stay quiet,
though you should eat the meal served.
That's manners!
Hmm, old man,
I shouldn't have forced him
to come to this dinner.
For today, just leave him alone.
But Toji,
to be given this precious meal
and not eat a single bite,
is incredibly disrespectful.
Hey Shinji!
Dad, Tsubame is going to wake up.
Well, let's clean up
and prepare the futon.
Here, for you, Miss Lookalike
and for Ikari too.
No, I'll take Ikari,
I think it's better this way.
It was quite unexpected.
The two of them getting married.
In middle school,
they'd do nothing but argue.
I guess the impetus was
the Near Third Impact.
All the hardships after that
forged their strong bond.
Ikari, even the Near Third Impact
did not bring just bring bad things.
If we get over this slope,
we'll be nearly there, Ikari.
Ah, there we are.
It's a self-built house made
using the remnants of the train station.
Feel free to use it.
The toilet is inside that car.
I'll get the fuel,
you can go on ahead.
Uhn! I'm naked.
How come you're not blushing at all
and don't look impressed?
Good grief!
Kenken really has a thing for picking up
depressed people like this.
I'm home.
Yeah, we've got a visitor.
I think he'll be staying a while.
For whatever reason, Shikinami
won't show her face in the village.
It's nothing.
There are so many Lilins,
it's just depressing.
Does he only react to the DSS Choker?
Kenken, you're too sweet with him.
Let him wipe himself.
Now, Ikari doesn't eat,
he can't do anything by himself.
A very painful thing
must have happened.
the kind of thing that is not common.
Closing his heart, so no one can see,
is a habit for him.
Just leave him alone.
Though he doesn't want to live,
he also doesn't just want to die.
Ikari, for now, this is enough.
Meeting again like this, there's a reason for it.
Count on me as much as you want.
You're my friend.
I'm happy that Ikari is alive.
Hmmm....
Division leader!
You don't have to worry...
Ha ha... thanks for
the hard work you do everyday.
Goodnight, dear.
What is "goodnight"?
Well, it's a magic formula to
give peace of mind and let everyone sleep.
Goodnight, Miss Lookalike.
Hmmm...
Ahhh...
Huuu...
I have had enough,
I'm tired of pretending to be asleep.
I wonder how long it will be
until I can sleep?
Ah, good morning.
What is "good morning"?
Well, it's a magic formula to
live together for the day.
Good morning, Miss Lookalike.
Kenken gets up every day at 6AM.
He's already left for work.
There's breakfast. Eat it!
She is are a very-tightly dressed girl.
Miss Lookalike, who we were asked to
help with by the doctor's wife.
Nice to meet you.
Miss Lookalike? Sounds like
a name with a story behind it.
Would you like to join a group?
You can do some work,
anything you like.
Work? If I'm ordered to, I'll do it.
It's not an order,
this is our job.
What is a "job"?
What do you mean "what is it"?
I never thought about it.
Well, it's something done
dripping with sweat by everyone.
"Sweat"?
Gently using three fingers,
straight from above.
It's a feeling coming from within.
Don't hold tightly,
just accompany it with your fingers.
After that, you just have to
get some practice.
Your tempo is slow,
try to match with everyone else.
Yes.
Is this "sweat"?
Oh... oh!
Ahh...
This is a job.
Hahaha, it's a seedling I planted.
That's to be expected.
Here, let me give you a hand.
Thanks for your work.
You've met the quota for the day.
This is special, since it's your first day
and you have worked hard.
At a time like this, what should I say?
"Thanks".
Thanks...
Let's all go the bathhouse!
What's a "bath"?
This is a bath.
It might be troublesome
if you keep your clothes on.
The bath is wonderful.
Unlike LCL, it's nice and warm.
Me, living without being ordered to...
why?
Being quiet,
lying down in a corner,
You just want to show
that you're in pain.
You're impeding my cleaning,
it's incredibly annoying.
Ah, that's not mum.
Welcome back, Miss Lookalike.
Thanks for your work today!
Sorry, I'm late.
Ah! Mum!
(Mother) Were you a good boy today?
(Boy) Yes!
Hahahaha.
Thanks as always, Hikari.
It's alright,
the feeling is mutual.
Well, let's go home.
Yes! Goodbye.
Right, goodbye.
What is "goodbye"?
Well, it's a magic formula to
make it so you'll meet again.
(Boy) Hurry!
(Mother) Suuure.
Let's play together at home.
What is that?
Well, it's a magic formula to
become good friends.
I'm already fed up.
Hnngh...
That is not easy on us either.
Throwing up again?
You brat!
Just being fed this kind of meal
you should be thankful!
You're still like the Lilin.
You won't survive without eating.
So eat!
For me, it's always only water.
Before you get a body that won't change at all,
you should taste the awfulness of this food!
Stupid brat!
Not doing anything that way,
is just not wanting to get hurt again.
As you're not busy,
at least try thinking
of why I got to the point of
wanting to hit you
at that time!
You're too mentally weak.
After all,
since everything you do backfires
and there's no way to recover
and it's all your fault,
you just don't want to do anything anymore.
Though it came from your father,
with that level of your mental fortitude
I wish you wouldn't have piloted
the Eva in the first place!
Sulk on your own, brat.
I'm home!
Ah, where is Ikari?
He left.
I see.
Leaving him be for now
might be the best solution.
Where did he go?
To the ruins near the northern lake.
The former site of Nerv's headquarters.
That's also fate.
Rations?
I forced him to eat.
He should last a while.
Thank you, Shikinami.
It's nothing.
It's not like I did it for him.
I just absolutely
won't let him die as he pleases.
My name?
Right, it won't do to continue
as "Miss Lookalike" as you have so far.
Though from what the doctor's said,
it seems you forgot your own name.
In that case,
how about giving yourself a new one?
Can I name myself?
A book? The one Ikari was talking about?
You picked it up,
you should bring it back.
Thanks.
Do you read?
I have been alone,
until now and from now on,
always alone.
That is obvious, Asuka.
Who's there?
Me.
Ahh, the First Pilot.
I'll open now.
I have heard that Ikari is here.
He's not here.
He run away.
I see.
Then I'll try looking for him.
Let me tell you something.
We, Eva pilots, are the same as the Eva,
constrained during design
not to surpass the framework of humans
The presence of inefficient emotions,
was just designed to match
the cognitive behaviour of humans.
All of you, the Ayanami Series,
You were adjusted
to take a liking to the Third Child.
Your feelings right now
were arranged by NERV from the start.
I see. But it's fine.
Because I feel glad.
Alright. Do what you want to,
The target of your affection is at
the remains of Nerv's Second Branch N109.
Thank you.
If you're going to him,
bring those rations.
Because he will soon be at his limit.
Do you live in this village
and not do any work?
Are you stupid?
This is not the place where I live.
It's the place I protect.
Ikari.
I was told to
"pick it up and bring it back".
I'll come again.
Is it a good idea to leave him on his own?
Leaving him like that,
I think it's dangerous.
For now, let's leave him be.
Ikari needs that kind of time.
Tough, Kensuke.
Aren't you a bit too cold towards Shinji?
Worrying too much is not good
for either one of us.
I'll be going back.
Let's wait and have some trust in him.
Yeah... you're right.
I hope Shinji will start to fit in
with the village soon.
Ikari,
why won't you come back to the village?
You're not doing anything here.
Are you also here to protect this village?
There's no protecting.
I destroyed everything.
I don't want to do anything anymore,
I don't even want to talk.
Don't make anyone else come!
I want to be left alone!
Why is everyone so happy?!
Because we like you, Ikari.
What?
Thanks. For talking to me.
This is a magic formula to
become good friends.
Huh, is the running away over?
Is it thanks to the First Pilot?
Yes.
Do you feel better now that
you've cried as much as you needed?
Yes.
I see.
Since it seems you can move now,
give a hand to Kenken.
Sometimes driving around is good.
It's a nice change of pace.
I was exonerated from agricultural labour,
the key industry of our village.
Since I'm a jack-of-all-trades.
The main task is an environment check
of the outer infrastructure, for today.
It's restless.
...though, the time has come
for the existing infrastructures.
They remain entirely suspended.
Since repair is difficult,
we leave them as is.
I only use branches that have fallen down
or have been pruned.
As we want to keep
the remaining forest safe.
We rely on the water here
for the life in the 3rd village.
It's essential to check
the amount of water here.
It truly is the water of life, directly
linked to the life or death of the village.
Take a look at the spring up ahead.
Since the road is harsh for you Ikari,
do some work here.
I'll entrust you
with gathering some materials.
No, I've never done it before,
I can't do it.
It's fine.
Tell me once you're done.
Be careful.
Our allotment for a week
is of one animal.
That is Wille's parting gift.
It's Life-Complement L-Barrier
Purification Obstruction Equipment.
Thanks to that, the 3rd village
can live without turning into core
Thanks to Misato and the others.
I have started watching them recently.
They've been named "Infinities"
The headless Evas, that were entirely
buried have suddenly started moving.
Today, I'm monitoring them.
As expected they won't come in
here because of the Sealing Column.
It's effective even against the Infinities.
Even a jack-of-all-trades can't do some things.
If that stopped working, I don't know what we'd do.
As you can see,
the situation is that we don't know
for how long we can stay here.
But until that time,
the best one can do is live.
That is umeboshi.
Every year my husband
looks forward to eating them.
Living is a repetition of
painful and pleasant things.
It's fine if everyday is the same
as today, that's just how it is
I'm at a very young time of my life.
I want to live well in the present.
And I also have Tsubame.
In fact, he is more attached than me.
It's alright if Miss Lookalike
remains here.
My name?
Right, have you decided?
No, nothing has come to mind yet.
Well, why not
let someone pick one.
Your name?
Right, I want you
to give me a name.
I want to stay here,
and I need a name for that.
So I want you to give me a name.
Even if you say to give you a name...
You are not Ayanami.
Any name will be good,
I want to be named by Ikari.
Is the First Pilot
moving properly?
Yes. She came today as well.
What is it?
Well... that's good.
Well then, Shinji.
You have gotten used to this place.
Yeah, somewhat.
That's good.
In this village,
many strangers got together.
With everything that happened,
finally everyone could settle.
Was it hard at first?
That's right...
Many terrible things took place.
It became a world where one
couldn't live remaining a lazy brat.
We too had to grow up fast.
We had to be able to do everything.
For my family,
I have done things I am not proud of.
In order to live,
I couldn't afford to remain so naive.
What I do is not something
as praiseworthy as being a doctor.
I play the doctor, help others
using what I have learned.
We have medical care equipment
that Kredit prepared, we're getting by.
Toji, you are praiseworthy.
You are helping people.
There are lives you can't help.
Taking on the sadness
and anger from those times.
I think is the duty of a doctor.
I'll carry on.
I'll have to make amends for what I did.
I want to take responsibility.
That's how I'll live.
Shinji, you have already fought enough
for everyone.
From now on,
you can just live here with us.
That's what I think.
Thanks for coming along
since this morning.
At that time, I didn't think the old man,
who survived the Near Third Impact,
would die like that in an accident.
If it's something like this,
you should talk about it.
I would have liked to have had a drink
and complain a bit.
Your father is still alive.
Even if you think it's useless,
you should meet him once
and talk properly.
You'll regret it.
It's too much for him.
That Ikari Gendo.
But you are father and son.
The bond remains.
It seems Matsukata's wife has had
an incredibly difficult delivery.
Good job!
I'm glad she was born safely.
Even the husband cried tears of joy.
Hey, you, you're laughing.
Yes, she's cute.
Truly.
The size is good,
how about a change of clothes?
Yes, let's try some different clothes.
How about these clothes now?
That's nice, it looks good on you.
I knew you'd look cute.
I want her as my daughter-in-law.
Is this embarrassing?
It's cute.
Sorry, it will be a bit hot,
but put this on for a while.
Since I'm a jack-of-all-trades,
I'm also in charge of contacting Kredit.
The restoration experiments are proceeding here,
where the L-barrier is relatively thin.
It's Kredit's outside lab.
Actually there's someone in the staff
I'd like to introduce to you.
Mr. Aida!
It's been a while.
Is that your new assistant?
Well, something like that.
It's the first time I have met
someone I don't know.
I'm Kaji, Kaji Ryoji.
What's your name?
So, Ikari,
he was a nice guy, right?
Yes,
but he said "Kaji"...
he's Misato and Kaji's son.
That 14-year-old
doesn't know his parents.
He's Misato's hope.
Since she can't do anything mother-like,
she decided to protect the child
just as Wille's leader,
without meeting him once in his life.
Then... what of Kaji?
He died.
Someone had to be sacrificed
in order to stop the Third Impact.
Kaji chose that.
Misato allowed it.
Misato deeply regrets making you, Ikari,
shoulder all the blame.
She said it should have been on her.
She doesn't want you to get in the Eva.
Isn't that the case?
Ikari, it's not just you
with painful things.
Misato has also been suffering.
Smell of soil?
Kaji...
Tomorrow, the Wunder
will come for a pick-up.
We've talked about the return route.
It's a record of the village
I was entrusted with by Misato.
Willecray's family is also in the picture.
And also, a letter from Toji's sister.
"Keep an eye on things" it seems to say.
Yes, understood.
I'm home.
Tears?
Is it me who's crying?
Is this loneliness?
Good morning, Miss Lookalike.
"Good night, good morning, thanks..."
"goodbye"
Good morning.
What is it? This early in the morning.
I wanted to meet you, Ikari.
Here.
Th..thanks.
Ehm... the name you asked for.
Ayanami is Ayanami.
I can't think of anything else.
Thank you for thinking of my name.
That's enough for me to be happy.
I can't live here,
but I do like it here.
Ayanami?
I'm aware that I like it.
I'm glad.
Ayanami? What's wrong?
I wanted to try to harvest rice.
I wanted to hold Tsubame some more.
I wanted to be together forever
with the people I like.
Goodbye.
Ahh, Ayanami!
Right, Miss Lookalike is over there...
What's wrong?
All right, all right, all right.
That is the Wunder.
It's huge.
Those with hope of departure are
getting off the ship.
Is it the decisive battle?
Ah, please don't take pictures.
Sorry,
just wanted to leave a record for today.
Right, do as you want.
Mmm...
What are you doing here?
Ikari, you can stay here.
Thanks Kensuke.
Please thank Toji and everyone else too.
Asuka, I'm going too.
Right, well,
this is regulation.
Suzuhara... Sakura?
You left on your own,
you got on the Eva you were told not to get on,
you idiot! Idiot!
You're a total idiot, Ikari!
Are you his wife?
Identification of the escapee concluded.
At the present time, I'll be taking over
the surveillance duty of BM-03.
Wartime Major Lieutenant Shikinami,
sign here for the delivery.
The DSS Choker?
No problem with having it unequipped.
Until the end of the whole operation,
you will remain in the anti-explosion isolation room.
BM-03, under surveillance,
has arrived in Chamber 2.
Ignition system ready.
Beside removing it forcibly,
that's a more reliable way to handle it.
In Magi Copy was left
the operation history of the choker.
That is,
it shows a situation in which
another pilot blew up
in front of his eyes.
Having experienced that kind of thing,
to come back to the Wunder...
Why?
Who knows.
That I got permission to join
from Captain Katsuragi
is a far greater mystery.
The records from the 3rd Village
and a private message from Suzuhara.
From my brother?
Chamber 2 completely closed.
Ignition system engaged.
Isolation of subject BM-03 completed.
No problem with
the cover of the crew disembarking.
Since the two new sites are so cool,
beginning, as planned,
the inclusion of Revised 8's power shift.
What's the condition of outside operations
and the main battery tower?
No problems with replacing the fourth
turret and adding the aft main gun.
Eva-related work outside is done.
We're about 3% behind.
Priority to speed.
Moving up to one fifth of the checks.
Yes sir!
5 minutes to resumption of
connection work of the second N1 rocket.
Recovery of Major Shikinami is done.
Though, why is that
pestilence spirit with her?
Leave it alone. It's preferable to
having him be of use to NERV again.
At the indicated time for Eva boarding, permission granted
to all personnel for unconditional use of weapons.
We'll be fine this time.
You're just saying that.
When I escaped before,
the captain wasn't able to get rid of me.
But now, that trust has become nothing.
He's just a kid.
Have some understanding for the hesitation.
That kid caused the Near Third Impact
and killed my whole family!
The Near Third Impact was the result,
not his intention.
The Captain is also
devoting herself to atonement.
Right.
Kaji is a person entrusted to Wille.
I'll trust the Captain in all respects.
Everyone is too soft with one's family.
I don't know whose pee it is,
it's the same as this regenerating water.
They think that if you cleanse it,
it's done.
That's not how it works!
Connection test for JA parts for
New Unit 02 completed without problem.
As planned, work on the
independent movement of the left wrist
can begin.
They increased the explosives.
Their trust in us has decreased.
I'm home.
Welcome back, Princess.
Thanks for your journey.
I really wanted to see you.
Dammit! What's with this room.
Instead of decluttering,
do you have even more books?
Books are the aggregation of human wisdom.
Reading widely books
from all times and places,
is my impossible dream.
By the way,
how did it go with Puppy Boy?
Nothing interesting.
Oh, you said you didn't care
about boys of his age.
What the brat needs is not a lover,
it's a mother.
All transfers from the supply ships
to the main ship are done.
All logistics personnel on the supply ship,
disembark immediately.
With Kredit's independent management,
Sign here to approve the removal of
all the limiters from both Evas.
Captain Katsuragi.
I validate the approval of both
the Captain and Vice Chief.
Maya, please start.
Understood, Vice Chief.
Misato, when you're alone,
you're always here.
The plate of the Captain's room.
It might be better to change to this.
You won't break your thoughts of
Ryo that easily.
It's not about Kaji.
Being here is just relaxing.
This block was
the original purpose of this battleship.
The preservation of the seeds of all life.
An ark to protect that, with the
possibility of operating semi-permanently,
an unmanned fully-automated model,
the AAA Wunder's original form.
For Kaji,
the continuation of the seeds of humanity
wasn't much of an issue.
He got involved with the Instrumentality
Project and disappeared.
The most important thing is leaving the world
in its natural state for all life-forms.
For this purpose, we'll have to evacuate
as many species of life as possible
from the range of the Earth.
This ship was in construction
to carry out this plan,
when we stole it from NERV.
We thought it impossible, stopping the
Instrumentality Project with our own power.
But in the end, by giving up our own life,
we stopped the Third Impact.
An incredibly troublesome man died
a self-contradicting, self-serving death.
The end result is that he isn't here.
And so, I'll use this ship
for the purpose of exterminating NERV
and stopping
the Humanity Instrumentality Project.
For you own revenge?
No, it's not an ark to save life,
it's a combat vessel to rescue life.
That's a really something,
coming from a mother.
I don't deserve that at all.
The Captain and Vice Chief are currently
on the Navigation Bridge.
Nerv's HQ has started to move.
It is thought to be in transit towards
the remains of the South Pole Epicenter,
followed by a soaring Black Moon.
The restoration of the Black Moon,
considered vital for the Fourth Impact.
As well as the Adams' vessels
to be sacrificed,
and the immaculate life-form,
made only of the pure sexless souls
the rebirth of
the Advanced Ayanami Series,
the Humanity Instrumentality Project
such that humans can bring salvation to humans.
This is where that arrogance has led you.
The Third Child has returned to Wille.
It seems Ayanami-Type6,
due to a lack of adjustment,
wasn't able to hold her individuality.
Is it so your son will be experience
the same loss that you did? Ikari.
He seems somewhat emotionally stable.
Captain Katsuragi, what do we do with
Temporary Name Ikari Shinji?
Will you not ever meet him,
same as your son?
Having him safe in the ship is enough.
There's no need for us to meet.
Are you still okay with not equipping
the DSS Choker?
If you have no intention of your own
to make up for your sins,
there's no meaning to atonement.
Misato,
even if you try to be cool about it,
aren't you really happy that
"he came back to you"?
I have seen that no good can come when
you let emotions get the better of you.
As always, you're harsh.
If I were to spoil you,
no good would come out of it.
Personal experience.
Despite not having
any other significant physical change,
just my hair grows.
How depressing.
In your hair reside
god, dirt, earthly desires.
it's the representation of
the heart of a chaotic person.
Princess, without any doubt,
it's proof that you're human.
That cursed epicenter
from the Second Impact.
The Adams' Vessels are all here.
The restart of Unit 13 is now
a matter of time.
Right.
Let's begin, Fuyutsuki.
I leave the rest to you.
So far, everything has gone
according to Seele's scenario.
Go, Shinji!
Don't do it for anyone else!
Do it for your own wish!
Captain, bad news.
Nerv's arrived at their final destination.
They're working for
the restart of Unit 13.
We're left with only a few hours then.
Yes.
Also, good news.
Construction of the suspension signal plug was completed.
Both Eva units at the very least. It's taken shape.
Understood.
All personnel, prepare for launch.
Suspend operations after 25 minutes.
After 30 minutes, we launch.
As always,
you're being reckless.
Departure will be after 25 minutes, with
everyone in second level battle stations.
Everyone shall finish their work
in 20 minutes.
Repeat, all ships prepare to launch
in a Type 1 battle formation.
Finalizing launch position for the unmanned fleet.
N1 rocket propellant injection completed,
switching to internal power supply.
Final status check is clear.
All off-ship personnel must leave immediately.
That's a few too many,
isn't it, Chief Takao?
When I decided to stand up against NERV,
it was for our companions who died.
When we insurrected, what I used
to identify my allies
was this bandana.
Yes, we will return to this colour
the land and the sea turned red.
It's the symbol of a vow
drenched in the colour of that wish.
Thank you.
This bandana was a memento
from Ryo.
Katsuragi, good luck.
At that time, I truly wished
to stay with Kaji.
I know you did.
If you didn't have a child,
I might have allowed it.
Because we are at battle stations,
I'm moving to the medical block.
Ikari, please don't move from there.
If something happens,
please call me with the red button.
Well, I'm off.
Plugsuits made for extreme depth,
indeed,
freshly prepared, nya.
These are unblemished, fresh ones,
right?
Clothes to die in, that is.
Activate the new EVA-02 JA reactor.
Start of stable output energy circulation.
No abnormalities in the New EVA-08
connection to the air carrier.
There's no need for a detachment test,
we'll just do it on the spot!
Last lock bolt of the cage released,
both Eva units fixed
and placed for launch.
Four-eyes, I need to make a quick stop.
Roger.
(Shinji) Huh?
(Mari) Guess who?
Hmmm... I don't know.
A hint: "Rooftop, glasses,
large breasts, nice girl"
The one with the parachute?
Correct!
I haven't introduced myself.
I'm Mari.
Makinami Mari Illustrious.
Once again, I'm pleased to meet you,
Wille's Puppy Boy.
Huh, you're a bit different.
The scent of an adult?
That brat won't change so easily.
For the last time, I'll ask.
Do you understand the reason why
I wanted to hit you?
When you went out with Unit 03...
because I didn't make any decision,
whether to save you or to kill you,
because I didn't want to
take responsibility.
You have grown up a little.
I'll say it, since it's the end.
When I ate your bento,
they were good.
At that time,
I thought I liked you, Shinji.
But... I grew up before you.
Well then.
Yo.
You did well.
Remarkable, Ikari Shinji.
See you later!
Princess, are you feeling a bit better?
I am, I'm relieved.
Both Eva pilots,
begin boarding of entry plugs.
Shinji, you should find peace
and your own place.
Fate will guide you.
We will meet again.
Yes... that's right, Kaworu.
Machine exceeding critical point.
Ascending thrust, 11.6 million tons.
No problem with the steering,
gyro-compass movements and gravity control.
Eva units fixing to launch positions
completed, entry starting.
Energy transmission normal.
Unmanned fleet,
all ship fixed in firing position.
Operations outside suspended,
emergency personnel standing by.
Transition to battle formation
Type-1 completed.
Captain,
the whole ship is ready for launch.
We can attack Nerv's HQ at any time.
Understood.
Message from the captain.
From now on,
this battleship will assault Nerv's HQ,
currently at the South Pole,
to prevent the irreversible Fourth Impact.
The objective is the neutralization of
Eva Unit 13, that will become
the trigger for the ritual.
Starting operation Yamato.
We'll bring an end to all the chaos so far.
All ships, launch!
Entry complete.
Completed transition of the command center
to the battle bridge.
Entering release point for
seeds containment units.
Understood.
Cut the link to the Wunder.
Switching to internal battery and
control system to independent system.
All seed units ejected.
Completed injection to L5 of all blocks.
No issues with self-adjustment.
Beginning descent to target location.
Breaking into the atmosphere.
Understood,
beginning entry into the atmosphere.
Monitors restored.
Approaching South Pole Epicenter,
entering L-Barrier limit surface.
Cruising through the barrier
with no issues.
Over the L-Barrier, that is there to stop
the life stained with the original sin.
We proceed without blessing to this area
that was cleansed of humanity.
It's thanks to Kaji's data
and the Anti-L System.
Still 20 to the possible point of
underwater navigation of the L-barrier.
Understood,
everyone prepare for underwater navigation.
Starboard second hull was shot!
Damage unknown!
We've found the shadow of
a ship at 3 o'clock!
Opfer-type equipped model 2 ship,
Erlösung!
Of course it was completed.
Sorry.
I'll go along with Ikari's selfishness
for a little longer.
Holding out until the reboot of Unit 13?
The same god-killing power,
how troublesome.
While keeping Nerv's ship in check,
hurry to the immersion point.
Attack!
We're getting shot from everywhere,
their firepower is overwhelming!
Damn, there's ships of
that same type somewhere!
There's a difference between
complete or incomplete.
Then the main ship is above!
We've reached the L-Barrier
immersion point.
Submerge quickly!
Understood.
We've surpassed the first layer
of the L-Barrier.
Breaking into second layer;
L-Barrier density plus 30.
Large number of Eva Infinity at 12 o'clock.
Don't mind that! Keep going!
At our 12 o'clock,
the shadow of a ship has appeared!
An ambush?
Three Erbsünde ships,
a successful pincer attack.
It's bad! If we get hit more than this,
it will hinder the navigation.
Keep the rudder as is, and proceed
at maximum battle speed!
Understood!
Third ship, evasive maneuver!
Don't let them escape!
This way we'll crash into them!
Rotate the ship!
180° roll!
Change stance with the enemy ship!
Understood.
Will he use the third ship as shield...
As always you act rashly.
We've passed the group of Infinity!
Passing the third layer of the B-Barrier!
Recognised our objective, Nerv's HQ.
Already below the Black Moon,
it's shifting.
Unit 13 restart is close.
Ship 2 and 3 are getting
closer from the stern.
There's no time make course to Nerv's HQ,
using the Black Moon as shield.
Preparing guided missiles,
aiming at Unit 13.
From our 6 o'clock,
Nerv's fleet is approaching!
Tilt the ship to keep the area
getting shot to a minimum.
Understood!
The stern gravity ballast was hit, down 20.
Focus the AT Field on protecting
the fleet above the main wings of ship.
Serious damage to the main battery
in the rear. We're getting beaten up!
Don't get distracted!
We have to resist until the shooting point.
10 until reaching the optimal point for
the launch of the guided missiles.
We've entered orbit!
Launch all guided missiles!
Recognised with optics
the final target, Unit 13!
As expected, before its restart.
Unit 13 is still not moving.
Identified Eva Series 7 approaching,
in very high numbers, immeasurable.
Ignore the small fish!
Hurry the launch of both Evas.
Maya, prepare the launch of both Evas.
Understood, preparing launch of both Evas.
Launch!
Please, Mari, Asuka.
Ah! Get out of my way!
Here, sorry!
Four Eyes, next target!
Will do.
Next!
Princess!
Nya-something!
They're passing through just like the Eva.
What a pain!
Four-eyes, give me a hand!
I know!
Both Eva units have landed at Nerv's HQ.
The target is below that blast hole.
These things...
they're so incredibly annoying!
After you, Princess.
I'm sorry Four-Eyes!
Eva Unit 13.
Just in time.
Even if I spoke of god's machine,
after all Unit 13 is a man-made all-purpose
humanoid weapon made by man.
If we drive into the core
the forced termination signal plug,
even without being able to destroy it,
it won't be moving anymore.
With this...
It ends...
An A.T. Field?
But Unit 13 shouldn't
have an A.T. Field.
How?
This is the Eva's own A.T. Field!
New Unit 2 is
scared of Unit 13?
Something's not right...
Gendo,
what are you scheming?
This is weird,
Nerv's battleship is withdrawing.
It's descending.
The cursed Epicenter
of the Second Impact.
Calvary Base.
The portal of hell is open again...
What?
Wings of light?
Are you trying to cause the Fourth with
the same method as the Second Impact?
No.
The ships built as watchmen to Guf
shouldn't be able to be used as triggers.
Also, the event enclosing the Black Moon
differs from the plan.
This is not in Seele's scenario.
It's a ritual we don't know.
Totally unexpected.
Is this Another Impact?
Whatever the conditions,
we'll completely destroy Nerv's plan!
Prepare the cannons!
Submerge ahead of the third ship!
Aim all possible cannons
to the third ship!
Start firing!
But in the building plan,
there's supposed to be even a fourth ship.
Attack!
What's the situation?
Direct hit! Both sides of
the 2nd hull were pierced!
Main battery tower down!
The fourth ship, Gebet!
We got into a trap.
For finishing the Impact,
this is essential.
So I have to destroy it now!
The prey is in front of me,
it's somewhat out of my control.
The last measure.
Sorry New Unit 02, once again
I'll be pushing you to the limit.
Releasing all limiters,
back-code 999.
Pattern blue! We have a response
to Angel 9 from within Nerv's HQ.
Princess! Are you going
to use the Angel's power?
Angel's Blood...
Total submersion!
Princess, do you plan on
discarding your humanity?
I'll neutralise New Unit 02's AT Field
with my own AT Field!
Wasn't it a Single Entry?
Damn it! Was Gendo's aim
the Princess' Angel transformation?
Shikinami type...
my original?
Wahhhhh!
The last Eva, in the same form of a god.
You too will just
accept me with love.
Come, this way.
Sorry to bother you.
Huh.
It's useless,
you silly person.
Asuka!
We've lost all signals from New Unit 02!
Pilot's conditions unknown!
We received serious damage by N2 Mine!
Damn! What is it this time?
It's something Eva-like,
it's clinging to us!
Pattern blue,
Eva Opfer type.
You built a new Mark 09,
pilot included?
This is bad! The inside of the ship
is being physically eroded.
Eliminate it, hurry!
I'm trying,
but the speed of infiltration
is too much, we can't make up for it!
Mark 09 is breaking through
the VD protective wall!
It's useless! Our controls
have been completely hijacked!
This thing is done for.
As expected, splendid work,
Fuyutsuki Vice Chief.
The reemergence of the artificial Lilith, as well as
the forced appropriation of the Spear of the Black Moon.
The stage is set. How will you
play the final scene to come, Ikari?
We've identified the intruder in the upper ship!
Commander Ikari!
I'm sorry Princess.
Truly the pinnacle of shame.
It seems we'll have to
back off for some time.
Yes.
It's been a long time.
Commander Ikari.
Thank you for your hard work so far,
Colonel Katsuragi.
We made use of
this ship as we planned.
You...
No point in arguing, it's the same as always.
No hesitation in accomplishing your goal.
Yes, it's something you taught me.
There are no barriers for a god.
You just have to accept
all that is coming.
Ikari Gendo.
Did you use the Key of Nebuchadnezzar
and throw away your humanity?
I have just added to my own body
the information that surpassed the logic
of this world. Without any problem.
I will kill God and will assemble
together Humankind and God,
holding the luxury of an Angel, I will accomplish
the evolution of Mankind and its complementation.
Is that the reason why
you used and discarded Asuka?
Ikari Gendo!
The Ayanami and
Shikinami Type Pilots,
were prepared from the start
for this very purpose.
Without any problem.
This is humankind's... no,
this is the commoditization of
the ancient life of this planet.
The transformation of every soul into Core,
being turned into Eva Infinity,
the beginning of the Fourth Impact?!
Exactly.
Purification of the Sea
by means of the Second Impact.
Purification of the Land
by means of the Third.
And then, Purification of Life
by the Fourth.
The materialization of the souls,
with Core shaped as the Eva Infinity.
To throw away the vessel
of the human species,
to invite to a stain-free heaven
of collective intelligence,
the final ritual.
Through the Second Impact,
your father, Dr. Katsuragi,
verified our hypotheses.
The Human Instrumentality Project.
I will for sure put a stop
to my father's nonsense.
For humanity, that has eaten the Fruit
of Knowledge, two fates were given by god.
To be destroyed by the Angels,
that have eaten the fruit of Life,
or to destroy the Angels
and steal their place,
to turn into children of god and continue
to live in eternity without knowledge.
We can only choose one or the other.
Nerv's Human Instrumentality Project,
Seele, which chose the latter,
made use of their Adams.
It is but a fleeting resistance to god.
It's worth the effort.
For us, who yielded to god,
following the Instrumentality Project,
there's no reset of despair,
we choose the continue of hope.
I believe in the will and the knowledge of humans,
who have surpassed even the power of god.
It's a difference in the way
we grasp the truth.
The world for Colonel Katsuragi,
and the shape of happiness for Akagi,
are unthinkable.
People's thoughts won't change a thing.
With this,
all the Horsemen have been gathered.
Then, I'll be taking back Eva Unit 01,
that you kept in custody.
Father!
We survived even the Near Third Impact.
Have trust in our own luck
and in Misato's Wille.
On the other side of the Doors of Guf,
the Minus Space that the Wunder
can't interfere with.
I'm sorry to say that for Wille there's
no way to stop the Instrumentality Project.
It's all over.
Misato.
I'll get in Eva Unit 01.
The way back where Ayanami disappeared.
Kaji taught me.
I could smell the soil.
I'll accept half of
what Misato is carrying.
For this reason I have decided
I will fight you, Ikari Gendo.
I want to make things right.
Wait a second,
don't mess around!
You really plan to get into the Eva?
I thought this could happen.
Captain, didn't we get authorization for unconditional
firing for this very situation?
Disease god! Because of the
Near Third Impact you brought about,
our lives have become so chaotic.
The main source of everything,
just you two, father and son...
I won't let it happen!
Sakura?
Ikari Shinji will not pilot the Eva.
Ikari getting into the Eva
brought unhappiness to everyone,
and I was unhappy myself.
So Ikari will not pilot the Eva again.
No, Sakura.
Please let me get into the Eva.
Don't be absurd, Ikari.
If you're hurt,
you won't have to ride anymore.
But being hurt is preferable
to getting into the Eva,
so please endure this!
Misato!
Captain!
It's alright, Shinji.
If you hadn't gotten into
Eva Unit 01 14 years ago,
at that time we would all
have been destroyed.
So thank you.
Even if the result was caused
by the Near Third Impact,
the responsibility for the action
you, Shinji, have taken, is solely mine.
Even now, Ikari Shinji,
you are my subordinate.
The responsibility for his actions
from now on,
will be mine alone.
I leave everything to you now, Shinji.
Sure!
Ikari is the benefactor who saved us,
but our father also disappeared
with the Near Third Impact.
Ikari is a benefactor and an enemy!
It's the only way!
That's enough!
Enough, Sakura.
Let's just think of living to see tomorrow.
Oh my god...
Sorry!
The preparations took a while.
Now, let's go!
Puppy Boy.
Maya, get the plugsuit
that's kept in the Captain's room.
I'll apply first aid now,
the bullet will melt immediately.
It's fine, Second Lieutenant.
Ikari Shinji.
The only things a son can do to his father
are giving him a pat on his shoulder,
or killing him.
It's just what Kaji told me.
Misato,
I have met Kaji Ryoji.
Is he well?
Yes.
I'm glad.
He was a very nice man.
Though I have spoken with him
only briefly, I like him.
Thank you.
Shinji, please always
be there for him.
I will.
Misato,
I'm off.
Take care.
Well, let's go back to the job.
The ship's worn out,
the main and support ships are still lost.
It will be a miracle
if we can just stay afloat.
That's fine.
Before we run out of reserve power,
an even greater miracle will occur.
With the Revised 8
in Overlap-compatibility form,
I'll capture the Adams Vessels,
thanks to the "plus four-in-one" status.
I'm thankful I can proceed easily
even in this Minus Space, nya.
Well then, Puppy Boy,
what you have to do,
before the Anti-L System stops completely
and everyone turns to Core,
is to destroy Unit 13.
We need to plan for its revival.
Alright, got it.
But of course,
Gendo will be
repeatedly quantum-teleporting,
taking advantage of the Minus Space.
So even catching him
will not be easy at all, nya.
It will be fine Mari.
I'm off!
Oh,
Puppy Boy, there's a possibility that the
soul of the Princess is inside Unit 13.
So please, the Princess...
save Asuka!
I'll try.
Ayanami.
Wherever you are,
I'll always come and meet you.
So please wait for me,
Shinji.
I will, thank you.
I'll be waiting.
Good Luck.
Are you done? Rei.
Ayanami.
Ikari, I'm sorry.
I wasn't able to make it so
you didn't have to pilot the Eva, Ikari.
It's alright.
Thank you, Ayanami.
I'll take care of the rest.
Yes, please.
We've received a signal from
the Minus Space via Revised 8!
Eva Unit 01 restart!
That's impossible!
Despite the disease god's
synch-rate being zero...
Could it be?
Shinji's true synch-rate is not zero,
but zero is the closest number to it?
Confirmed.
Synch-rate is Infinity.
Oh, has it changed into
the Spear of Hope, Cassius?
Stop, father!
Ah.
It's useless.
There's something... I have to do myself!
Until Another Impact is forced to happen,
what does that man intend to do?
As an objective of Another Impact,
there's only one thing I can think of.
The creation of a Spear
made for the Fourth.
The two Spears were preserved until
the end for the sake of the Additional.
I'm afraid that it was done
for that one single desire.
Absurd, it's just his ego.
We'll soon be able to meet again, Yui.
Don't move.
Get away from it, father!
What is that?
The Golgotha Object.
Someone that is not a human,
has left here the world of god
together with the Adams and the 6 Spears.
My wife... your mother was also here.
The beginning of everything,
the Promised Land.
It's the one and only place where one can
change their destiny,
that is otherwise out of human's control.
Here?
The Eva Cage?
What is this place?
It's the world of your memories.
Father.
We can't understand the Minus Space
with our sensory functions.
Therefore, the LCL molds it into
a virtual world we can perceive.
Just give me Unit 01.
If you do so, you too
will be able to meet your mother again.
This is why I don't like children,
opposing a futile resistance.
We'll have to take a detour.
What's this? It moves the same way I do.
It's not easy!
Eva Unit 13.
The machine of despair,
counterpart of the Unit 01 of hope.
They conform to one another,
they get in tune.
This too is a necessary ritual.
Stop it already, father!
It's pointless.
With so little strength,
there's no way you can stop me!
Do you still not understand?
Even with strength, you're no match.
Not to mention violence and fear.
Because that's not the way
we settle things!
That's right.
This won't be settled with strength.
Right.
I want to talk with you, father.
Father.
What do you want to do here?
It can happen only by using
this Golgotha Object.
The Additional Impact.
That will lead to
the path of my deicide.
That is why the last two Spears
have been brought here.
As we thought,
Magi Copy is predicting
a high probability Commander Ikari will
use and then dispose of the two Spears.
If we lose all the spears,
won't Shinji also lose the means
to stop the activation?
What should we do?
We'll make new Spears ourselves
and take them to where he is.
What are going to do
if we can't do that?
When the ship was taken over as the Buße,
it used materials from the Black Moon
to create an unknown Spear.
So, using this ship, we should be able
to make new Spears ourselves.
Putting humanity's will into the Wunder,
an even bigger miracle is possible.
I trust in Ritsuko's knowledge,
and in Wille and Wunder's
mysterious power.
Don't be absurd.
The only sample I have
is the activation data from earlier.
For you, that's more than enough.
Right, I'll try.
What we need is likely
in the spinal cord coupled system.
Sorry Maya, we're going to do this
without any preparation.
That's no problem, Vice Chief.
It's what we always do.
Chief engineer! The reserve power and
the spinal cord coupled system are safe.
Let's finish the rearrangement
work directly.
It won't do! You evacuate,
even just remaining here is dangerous!
It's the last public service.
We'll do all we can!
This is what young men are for.
Then, before Commander Ikari does
anything, we'll support Shinji.
Yes sir!
Unit 01's Pilot,
there's something I want to show you.
This is... a Black Lilith?
That's the way it is in your memory.
The Imaginary Evangelion,
predicted by Dr. Katsuragi,
a fictitious, imaginary Eva that shouldn't
exist in this world.
You can recognise that only human beings
believe in the equality of fiction and reality.
The Spears of Hope and Despair
become together trigger and luxury.
Fiction and reality melt together, and
everything becomes the same information.
This is my perception. In other words,
the beginning of an Additional Impact
to rewrite the world.
The only way to realise my desire.
Is this the Additional Impact?
Yes, that is possibly
the Imaginary Evangelion.
To think it actually exists.
This is weird.
Definitely weird!
Hmmm. Finally, it has begun.
You?
It's been a while, Professor Fuyutsuki.
By the way, isn't the L-Barrier density
too high in this ship?
Yes, it wasn't originally
meant to be manned.
I recognise it's impossible.
People are always given
a light called "hope".
But it's the nature of humanity
to cling to the sickness of hope and drown.
Both me and Ikari have been
clinging too much to the sickness of hope.
Gendo intends to make his desire
come true by making himself
the Center of Instrumentality.
I want to help with that... no.
Though I understand your feelings of
repeating your wishes, Fuyutsuki,
I don't want
all of humanity to be involved, nya.
I guess,
my role is over.
I have gathered what you wanted,
the rest is up to you.
Maria Iscariot.
Hah... I haven't heard that name
in a very long time.
Then, this is farewell.
Yui, is this good?
It moved, this can work!
Captain, for what's next,
the crew we have here is enough.
Understood,
all personnel, leave the ship.
All personnel, evacuate!
I repeat, all personnel, evacuate!
Hurry to the escape capsules!
There's a whole bunch of Eva Opfer-type,
in the capacity of the Adams Vessels.
As one would expect, Professor Fuyutsuki's
performance was good, nya.
I'm sorry, you'll have to become
the nourishment for the Overlap!
With this, 8 + 9 + 10!
Plus 11!
Let's go for the last one!
Closure of escape capsules up to number 4.
Please hurry to capsule number 5!
I have returned to the cockpit.
Now, surviving is our job.
However tough it gets.
Captain, the rearrangement work is done.
I think we're good to go.
Understood.
Bring all control systems to
the Captain's seat, then leave the ship.
Misato?
Someone has to make sure
this operation proceeds.
And the person responsible for this ship
is me.
Take care of the children and
the life that remains, Ritsuko.
I understand, Misato.
I'll do my best.
Thank you.
Only a bit of reserve power left,
the last thing you want to rely on,
the old...
reaction-propulsion engine.
The Lilin won't have a use
for you guys anymore.
Sleep well,
Adams.
The Wunder has moved.
Let's hurry to the meet up, nya.
To think that the complementation of both
the physical and mental aspects of humanity
was activated at the same time.
Gendo, you are...
Father, what do you wish for?
The disappearance of the AT Field
you didn't choose yourself,
a single world of mind,
with the whole of humanity being equal.
Without differences between people.
Without rich and poor, discrimination,
conflict, abuse, pain, sadness.
A world of purely cleansed souls.
And then I will meet with Yui again.
A peaceful world.
Father, stop already.
Why.
Why are you here, Shinji?
Because I want to
let you know something.
Even when I was lonely,
I never tried to get closer to you.
I was afraid you would realise
that you hated me.
But now, I want to know
about you, father.
The A.T. Field,
did you abandon humanity for me?
Were you actually afraid of me?
Of me...
I wasn't supposed to throw this away,
but to give it to you, father.
We're the same.
Yes, you're right.
The headphones cut me off
from the outside world.
A cover of indifference.
It protected me
from the noise of others.
<But, after meeting Yui,
it became unnecessary.>
Have you chosen the name?
If it's a boy, "Shinji",
if it's a girl, "Rei".
Shinji. Rei.
<Not knowing the love of a parent,
I will become a father.>
<Of course, this world is
unstable, imperfect, irrational.>
<In this world, even taking others
by their word won't go well.>
<At different times,
people say different things.>
<which is the truth,
which to go along with.>
<Maybe, both can be true
for that person.>
<It was just a change
in their feelings of the time.>
<I hated the world
overflowing with people.>
<Since I was a child,
solitude was ordinary.>
<But in the world, there are
people who don't deem it acceptable.>
<I didn't like going to
other people's houses.>
<I despised being taken along to the houses
of uninteresting classmates and relatives, >
<and being imposed on the information and
fulfillment of that lifestyle.>
<Since I was a child,
there have been two things I liked.>
<Knowledge obtained unilaterally
sated the hunger of my mind.>
<Concerns are not needed for knowledge.
As long as there was time, >
<A tuned sound returns
the correct note of the keys.>
<In that, there's no lie.
There's no betrayal, no disappointment.>
<Silently, I was changed
by the flow of music.>
<I liked that system.
I liked being alone.>
<Neither I nor other people nor anyone
being hurt. Being alone was peaceful.>
<I had lost my confidence
in living alone.>
<For the first time I knew
the suffering of solitude.>
<I merely wanted to change myself
by being close to her.>
Due to my weakness,
I can't meet Yui.
Shinji...
I think it's because you
wouldn't recognise that weakness.
Did you know all along?
Father.
What is it?
It's certainly Misato.
Still more!
Ugh!
What... the "Holy Spear"
is completely lost.
The new Spear to rewrite the world
is supposed to be impossible.
The Spears given by god,
Cassius, the Spear of Hope,
and Longinus, the Spear of Despair,
even if we lose them, we'll have Gaius,
the Spear newly made with
with the power of our determination
to return the world the way it was.
Or better, Wille's Spear.
Humanity, that holds knowledge and determination,
without any help from god,
has come this far, Yui.
I've got it!
Mari! Get Shinji!
Of course!
I'll definitely bring him home.
Please! Ugh!
While I'm still unable to meet with Yui,
the new Spear was brought here.
Unfortunate.
Mother, it's the only thing
you can do.
Sorry Ryoji.
Thank you, Misato.
Shinji, you have grown up to be able to
accept the thoughts and death of others.
<As material for
the reconstruction of Yui, >
< to the end, I didn't understand
whether Shinji was necessary or not.>
<With the fulfillment of my desire,
comes a reward.>
<I felt the child was
a punishment for me.>
<I was convinced that not meeting, nor having
a relation with the child, was my atonement.>
<I believed that way would even
be better for the child.>
I'm sorry, Shinji.
I see...
Is that where you were, Yui?
Ikari Gendo.
He is the Center of Instrumentality
this time, the origin of the circle.
I'll take over from here.
Ikari Shinji,
what do you wish for?
I'm good.
Even if there's pain, I think it's alright.
More than myself,
I want to help Asuka and everyone else.
That's right.
You were already recovering,
not in the Imaginary, but within Reality,
Yes.
I want to make right what father did.
Asuka.
I don't know my papa,
mama is not here either.
So you don't need anyone, Asuka.
<There's no one
and I'll make it right.>
<Even if I'm disliked by people,
even if they bad-mouth me, >
< it doesn't matter,
as long as I pilot the Eva.>
I don't need anyone,
I have a strong body and mind.
(Gendo) Wow.
(Yui) Haha.
Phew.
It's fine.
Asuka is Asuka.
That is enough.
Was I asleep?
Stupid Shinji.
I'm glad we could meet again.
I just wanted to tell you this.
Thank you,
for telling me "I like you".
I also liked you, Asuka.
Goodbye, Asuka.
Say hi to Kensuke.
Princess, be well.
She is gone.
Shinji, won't you be lonely?
I'll be alright.
Now it's your turn, Kaworu.
I remember.
I have come here many times and met you.
Because your name
is written into the "Book of Life".
We'll keep meeting indefinitely.
I am you.
We're the same.
That's why I was drawn to you,
I wanted to make you happy.
Yeah.
Kaworu, you resemble my father.
That's why we piloted the same Eva.
You're somewhat different than usual,
Shinji.
Will you not cry?
No. With tears,
I can only save myself.
Even if I cry, I can't save anyone else.
So I won't cry anymore.
I see.
You have already grown up.
Though I'll be a bit lonely, it's alright.
Kaworu, I will get rid of your Eva,
Unit 13.
Yeah, you can throw it away.
I'm sorry.
I misunderstood your happiness.
Yes, that was your happiness,
Commander Nagisa.
<The only thing that can erase my existence
is vacuum decay>
<So I will have to
forever repeat my part>
It's a magic formula
to become good friends.
I desire a world of complementarity.
You never change, Shinji.
Because of that you choose him,
you wrote his name in the Book of Life.
Thank you.
I was also saved by Ryo.
It's an honour, Commander Nagisa.
I don't like that, Ryo.
Please start calling me "Kaworu".
Not yet, Commander Nagisa.
The shore is the space between
the sea and the land.
He is the first Angel,
he'll become the 13th Angel.
It's a name very much like you,
who weaves the threads of humanity.
You've carried out your duty well.
Now, even if you hand it over to him,
it should be fine.
What about working the fields
with Katsuragi in your old age?
Yeah, that's also good.
You're the only one left, Ayanami.
I'm good here.
The other you has already found
a place to belong to that isn't here.
When Asuka comes back, I think
she too will find a new place to belong.
Ikari, I wanted for you the happiness
of not piloting the Eva.
I know.
That's why this isn't the place.
There's a way to live for you.
Really?
Really.
I have also chosen a way to live
without piloting the Eva.
I won't turn back space and time, just...
I'll just rewrite it to a
"good world without EVA"
To a new world people can live in.
A new creation of the world.
Neon Genesis.
Yes.
Besides, Mari will come to get me later.
So don't worry.
Right, I understand.
Thank you, Ikari.
Yeah...
I will try, Ayanami.
Neon Genesis.
♪ Voyager - Gravestone Without Dates ♪
Haa!
Who...?
<Father wanted to see mother off,
right?>
<That's the deicide that
father wished for.>
Yeah! I made it.
Just barely on time.
Mari!
Thank you, Units 8+9+10+11+12.
Good job, last Evangelions.
Mari!
I have kept you waiting, Shinji.
Train arriving momentarily,
please step black from the yellow line.
Whoooo is that?
Large breasts, nice girl.
Right answer.
As always, you smell nice.
Is that the scent of an adult?
You're as cute as always.
Ohoh,
you've become a smart mouth.
♪ *One Last Kiss* ♪
Well, let's go, Shinji.
Yes, let's go.
♪ "Beautiful World" ♪
By fefemess and sackboy97